[
  {
    "id": "71046",
    "question": "What is a cpu?",
    "answer": "Brain of the computer,  it has all the circuity needed to proccess input, store data  and output results.",
    "options": [""]
  },
  {
    "id": "63888",
    "question": "What can the proccessor perform?",
    "answer": "1) Basic arithmetic 2) Logic Control 3) Input/Output",
    "options": []
  },
  {
    "id": "5418",
    "question": "CPU principle components:",
    "answer": "1) ALU (Arithmetic Logic Unit) \\n2) Processor Register \n3) Control Unit",
    "options": []
  },
  {
    "id": "39249",
    "question": "Purpose of cache:",
    "answer": "Used to reduce the average time to access memory",
    "options": []
  },
  {
    "id": "44313",
    "question": "What is fetch fase:",
    "answer": "when the (Instruction Register) gets data from the ram.",
    "options": []
  },
  {
    "id": "55771",
    "question": "Proccessor register:",
    "answer": "1) Temprorly store and maniplate values 2) Sends operands to the ALU and store the registers from them",
    "options": []
  },
  {
    "id": "1919",
    "question": "Control Unit:",
    "answer": "1) Fetch 2) Excution Cycle 3) Decode",
    "options": []
  },
  {
    "id": "54736",
    "question": "ISA",
    "answer": "Introduction Set Architectures",
    "options": []
  },
  {
    "id": "71928",
    "question": "What does ISA serves?",
    "answer": "It serves the interface between software and hardware.",
    "options": []
  },
  {
    "id": "99870",
    "question": "3 popular ISAs today:",
    "answer": "x86 by intel, ARM by ARM LTD and RISC-V open source",
    "options": []
  },
  {
    "id": "61020",
    "question": "What is an Embedded system?",
    "answer": "A combination of computer hardware and software designed for a specific function.",
    "options": []
  },
  {
    "id": "10751",
    "question": "Examples of embedded systems:",
    "answer": "Gps trackers, Central heating, Medical devices, Arduino",
    "options": []
  },
  {
    "id": "44051",
    "question": "Components of embedded systems:",
    "answer": "Power SUpply, proccessor, memory, timers, serial communication ports, system application specific cicuits",
    "options": []
  },
  {
    "id": "64851",
    "question": "Typical peripherals for embedded:",
    "answer": "Serial communication Interfaces (SCI), Inter Integrated Circuit (I2C), Universal Serial Bus (USB), Multimedia Cards (SD cards), Network, General purpose Input/Output (GPIO)",
    "options": []
  },
  {
    "id": "4426",
    "question": "Communication protocols in embedded systems:",
    "answer": "1) Inter system protocol 2)Intra system protocol",
    "options": []
  },
  {
    "id": "94574",
    "question": "Inter system protocol",
    "answer": "External communication between devices",
    "options": []
  },
  {
    "id": "26118",
    "question": "Intra system protocol",
    "answer": "Internal communication between components in the circuit board",
    "options": []
  },
  {
    "id": "64357",
    "question": "Example of Inter system:",
    "answer": "USB, UART, USART",
    "options": []
  },
  {
    "id": "17328",
    "question": "Example of Intra system protocol:",
    "answer": "SPI, I2C, CAN",
    "options": []
  },
  {
    "id": "51444",
    "question": "Program Unit:",
    "answer": "Set of instructions that a computer follows in order to perform a particular task.",
    "options": []
  },
  {
    "id": "27779",
    "question": "Subprogram:",
    "answer": "A statement which can be reused to save memory space and coding time.",
    "options": []
  },
  {
    "id": "10752",
    "question": "Example of a subfunction:",
    "answer": "Functions, methods, prodcedures",
    "options": []
  },
  {
    "id": "78055",
    "question": "Parameter evalution (Definition):",
    "answer": "The proccess of mapping formal and actual parameters when a subprogram is called.",
    "options": []
  },
  {
    "id": "75003",
    "question": "Parameter evalution:",
    "answer": "1)Formal parameters are declared once. 2)Actual parameters (arguments) are declared in the call, 3)Formal list is determinative to parameter evalution",
    "options": []
  },
  {
    "id": "12930",
    "question": "Pass by value:",
    "answer": "Both parameters refer to the same memory location",
    "options": []
  },
  {
    "id": "60608",
    "question": "Pass by value:",
    "answer": "We will copy the vlaues to the formal parameter",
    "options": []
  },
  {
    "id": "38782",
    "question": "Block:",
    "answer": "A structure of source code, it can contain one or more declarations and statements.",
    "options": []
  },
  {
    "id": "11246",
    "question": "Scope:",
    "answer": "The palce wheere an item (variable, function, method, constant, ..etc) that has an identifier name is recongnized.",
    "options": []
  },
  {
    "id": "92167",
    "question": "Abstract data type (ADT):",
    "answer": "Objects whose behaviour is defined by a set of values and a set of operation, for example: stacks and queues",
    "options": []
  },
  {
    "id": "50390",
    "question": "Generic programming:",
    "answer": "It is to allow type (integer, string, objects) to be parameters to classes and interfaces.",
    "options": []
  },
  {
    "id": "34978",
    "question": "Control systems:",
    "answer": "It consists of subsystems or proccesses assembled for the purpose of controlling the output of the process.",
    "options": []
  },
  {
    "id": "34702",
    "question": "Example of control systems:",
    "answer": "Air conditioner maintaining temprature of the room, a lift moving upwards.",
    "options": []
  },
  {
    "id": "44804",
    "question": "Gain and phase margin:",
    "answer": "Can be derived from bode plot, which is used to know the stability of a system.",
    "options": []
  },
  {
    "id": "28657",
    "question": "Gain margin (GM):",
    "answer": "The amount of again which can increase ofr decrease without making the system unstable.",
    "options": []
  },
  {
    "id": "46225",
    "question": "Phase margin (PM):",
    "answer": "The amount of phase which can increase or decrease without making the system unstable.",
    "options": []
  },
  {
    "id": "83580",
    "question": "Linear Systems:",
    "answer": "A system whose output for a linear combination of inputs are the same as linear combination of indivisual responses to those inputs",
    "options": []
  },
  {
    "id": "85212",
    "question": "Transfer function(definition):",
    "answer": "The realtionship between the output signal of control system and the input for all possible input values.",
    "options": []
  },
  {
    "id": "34158",
    "question": "Transfer function:",
    "answer": "The transfer function for any LTI system is the laplace transform of the impulse response of the LTI system.",
    "options": []
  },
  {
    "id": "58575",
    "question": "Netweork layers:",
    "answer": "Physical, Data link, Network, Transfer, Session, Presentation, Application.",
    "options": []
  },
  {
    "id": "63284",
    "question": "TCP(Transmission control unit):",
    "answer": "Communication standard that enables applications, programs and computing devices to exchange messages over the network.",
    "options": []
  }
, {"id":"11433", "question":"How does the tcp make sure that both sides are ready to transfer data?", "answer":"sing 3 way hand shake.", "options":[]}, {"id":"68494", "question":"UDP (User datagram protocol):", "answer":"Used to establish low latency and loss tolerating connection between applications on the internet.", "options":[]}, {"id":"50966", "question":"How does the UDP work?", "answer":"It is connectionless, so it does not garantuee data delivery.", "options":[]}, {"id":"71720", "question":"Combinational Logic design:", "answer":"A type of digital logic desgin that is implemented by boolean circuits, where the out put is a pure function of the present input.", "options":[]}, {"id":"594", "question":"Multiplexer:", "answer":"Adevice that selects between several digital input signals and one out put only.", "options":[]}, {"id":"76531", "question":"Demultiplexer:", "answer":"Combinantional logic circuit that can have multiple outputs with single input.", "options":[]}, {"id":"94721", "question":"Encoders:", "answer":"A combinantional logic circuit, used for binary operations like addition and subtraction.", "options":[]}, {"id":"97476", "question":"Decoders:", "answer":"Combinational logic circuits and it is oposite of encoders, used in code conversions, high performace memory systems and data disturibution.", "options":[]}, {"id":"6478", "question":"Digital comparators:", "answer":"Combinational circuit desgined to compare two inputs.", "options":[]}, {"id":"63254", "question":"Parity generators:", "answer":"Used for error detection during data transmission.", "options":[]}, {"id":"23188", "question":"Arithmetics Logic Unit (ALU):", "answer":"Combinational ciruit and part of a CPU that performs arithmatic and bitwise operations.", "options":[]}]
